<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors on Científicos Mexicanos en el Extranjero</title>
    <link>/authors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Authors on Científicos Mexicanos en el Extranjero</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019-{year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/abigail/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/abigail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abigail Jiménez Franco currently works at the Department of Crystallography, Mineralogy and Mineral Deposits, University of Barcelona, applying electron microscopic techniques to the micro and nano-scale to mineral characterization with focus in hydro-thermal systems. Currently, she is collaborating in Caribbean Lithosphere (CALOR) and &amp;lsquo;Proyecto de Geoparque Comarca Minera de Hidalgo&amp;rsquo; projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/admin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Somos un grupo de jóvenes Científicos Mexicanos en el Extranjero que colaboramos con diversas instituciones de investigación en México. Estamos comprometidos con la sociedad y nuestra motivación es estrechar la brecha que existe entre el conocimiento científico especializado y el saber popular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hemos visto con preocupación cómo las redes sociales han sido una vía para la propagación de noticias falsas (fake news) y rumores que solo infunden incertidumbre y confusión. Queremos revertir este fenómeno y convertir estos medios en el conducto para acercarnos a la sociedad y que encuentres una alternativa confiable para informarte. También queremos poner a tu alcance nuestro trabajo científico.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/adan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/adan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I received the M.Sc. and Ph.D. degrees in computer science from the Center for Research and Advanced Studies of the National Polytechnic Institute (CINVESTAV-IPN), Mexico, in 2012 and 2017, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main research interests involve the study and design of data clustering techniques based on nature-inspired metaheuristics and their applications to problems from areas such as digital image segmentation and machine learning. Recently, I have been focused on the development of a multiobjective evolutionary approach for multi-view data clustering and its application to a range of application domains, ranging from network analysis to medical imaging data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/jesus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/jesus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Doctor in Astrophysics with 7 years of expertise in research. Mostly on the development of numerical/computational tools for physical and astrophysical simulations. I have a high expertise in programming, data analysis and problem solving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am creative, innovative, analyst and hard worker. During my PhD studies I developed high programming skills in several languages such as Python, R, Fortran, C++, Shell, etc., and version control tools like Git using platforms such as GitHub and Bitbucket. I worked on developing sophisticated numerical tools which were implemented to simulate blazars flares (prompt high energy radiation from relativistic jets of active galactic nuclei). This has shown my fast learning skill of new programming languages and develop efficient codes to solve the problem posed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am coauthor of three articles in peer reviewed scientific journals and author of a doctoral thesis, qualified as innovative, in which several numerical and programming issues were overcome, reason why it received the distinction of excellent. In addition, I have good English skills which makes me capable of discussing and interact fluently in both Spanish and English.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/rosamaria/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/rosamaria/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My name is Rosa Maria Vargas Magaña I recently (August 2017) received my Ph.D. in Mathematical Sciences from the Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México at (IIMAS), working on non-local shallow water wave models over variable topography under the supervision of  Dr. Panayotis Panayotaros.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My principal research interests are: Nonlinear waves, Hamiltonian systems, Surface water waves, Pseudo-dierential operators, Numerical analysis, Fluid dynamics, Geophysical and Engineering applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/abril/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/abril/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/adriana/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/adriana/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/andrea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/andrea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am a chemist with a vivid curiosity about biological phenomena and their interface with chemistry and physics. During my bachelor I was interested on the physical chemical basis of the protein crystallization phenomenon and studied the influence of electric fields to enhance molecular packing and crystal quality. On an early stage of my PhD I was focused on the rational design of chimerical variants of TIM barrel enzymes with enhanced stability. At a later stage, I highlighted the importance of protein flexibility on the susceptibility of proteins to aggregate and I described a new quantitative parameter of proteins called thermal flexibility. This concept proposes that proteins with a higher stability have a wider conformational space available when thermal energy is provided, which means that energy can be stored in many more microstates than a protein with a lower stability. This fact confers the protein with a large resilience to thermal changes. I developed this concept during my PhD to explain the differences in stability of TIM proteins, but since its publication in a Q1 journal, thermal flexibility has been cited for other research groups as a possible cause of the thermostability of different kind of proteins, such as phytases, k-like proteases, serum amyloid A and globins. I obtained my degrees with honors from Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México (UNAM) and obtained grants from the Mexican Government during all stages of my career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After my PhD, I assumed a job as a project manager to conduct outreach activities (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.redproteinas.com&#34;&gt;www.redproteinas.com&lt;/a&gt;) while continuing doing research as a collaborator of research groups in Mexico and USA. In November 2018 I was granted by the Mexican Government to join an interdisciplinary team at the Cell Structure and Dynamics at the University of Lisbon in Portugal. Here I am aligning my expertise on protein interactions and stability with my aims to contribute to cellular models of protein aggregation and neurodegeneration. I have co-authored two peer-reviewed papers and published a book chapter and two research papers as a first author, one of them also as a co-corresponding author. My research is focused on finding key molecular interactions governing protein aggregation and disease using an interdisciplinary approach from computational simulations to molecular biology and live cell imaging.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/marce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/marce/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/nell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/nell/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/pacupe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/pacupe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I received the M.Sc. and Ph.D. degrees in Physiology, Biophysics and Neurosciences from the Center for Research and Advanced Studies of the National Polytechnic Institute (CINVESTAV-IPN) of Mexico, in 2007 and 2016, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My scientific focus is the genetic expression regulation on eukaryotes. My research experience is on epithelial physiology using cellular and molecular biology approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, I am a postdoctoral researcher at the University of Texas Southwestern medical center (UTSW).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
